<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cryptography | Chalmers Security &amp; Privacy Lab</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/tag/cryptography/</link><atom:link href="https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/tag/cryptography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Cryptography</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 10:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/media/icon_huf405b5a3d64669240eafa59ffeef17e8_561926_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url><title>Cryptography</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/tag/cryptography/</link></image><item><title>Succinct PPRFs via Memory-Tight Reductions</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2025/2025-04-08-chris/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2025/2025-04-08-chris/</guid><description>&lt;p>Chris Brzuska is a faculty member of the departments computer science as well as mathematics and systems analysis at &lt;a href="http://www.aalto.fi/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Aalto University&lt;/a> in Finland. His research area is cryptography and its connections to related areas such as IT security, verification and complexity theory. Until March 2018, he was a junior professor at &lt;a href="http://www.tuhh.de/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TU Hamburg&lt;/a> in Germany and held the chair for IT Security Analysis in collaboration with and supported by &lt;a href="http://www.nxp.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NXP Semiconductors&lt;/a>. Until September 2015, he was a post-doctoral researcher at Microsoft Research Cambridge, UK. Until September 2014, he was a post-doctoral researcher at &lt;a href="http://www.tau.ac.il/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tel-Aviv University&lt;/a> working with &lt;a href="http://www.eng.tau.ac.il/~bennyap/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Benny Applebaum&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.cs.tau.ac.il/~iftachh/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Iftach Haitner&lt;/a>. Until October 2012, he was a PhD student advised by &lt;a href="http://www.fischlin.de/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Marc Fischlin&lt;/a> at &lt;a href="http://www.tu-darmstadt.de/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TU Darmstadt&lt;/a>. During his PhD, he also visited &lt;a href="http://cseweb.ucsd.edu/~russell/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Russell Impagliazzo&lt;/a> at &lt;a href="http://www.ias.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">IAS&lt;/a> from October 2011 to March 2012. Before, he studied mathematics in Duisburg-Essen, Bordeaux and Darmstadt with the key aspects cryptography, logic and lattice theory (partial orders)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://chrisbrzuska.de/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Chris Brzuska&amp;rsquo;s webpage&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Two-Round, Ideally Secure, Strong Asymmetric PAKE</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2025/2025-04-03-kelsey/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2025/2025-04-03-kelsey/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kelsey Melissaris is a cryptographer. She received her PhD from the City University of New York, and wrote her thesis on authenticated key exchange. Most recently, she was a postdoctoral fellow at Aarhus University’s Cryptography and Security Group, researching threshold cryptography and digital signatures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.kelseymelissaris.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kelsey Melissaris&amp;rsquo;s webpage&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Consistency-or-Die: Consistency for Key Transparency</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2024/2024-10-17-lucia/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2024/2024-10-17-lucia/</guid><description>&lt;p>Lucia Lavagnino is currently an Erasmus Trainee at the Chalmers CryptoTeam. Lucia received her Masters Degree in Mathematics from Università degli studi di Torino in 2024. During her studies, Lucia took a 6 month Erasmus internship at Linnaeus University (Växjö) with focus on mathematical aspects of cryptography.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.chalmers.se/en/persons/luciala/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lucia Lavagnino&amp;rsquo;s webpage&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CaSCaDE: (Time-Based) Cryptography from Space Communications DElay</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2024/2024-09-19-elena/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2024/2024-09-19-elena/</guid><description>&lt;p>Elena Pagnin is an assistant professor at the CSE department at Chalmers, leading the Cryptoteam. Her research is focused on cryptography and security, with a special interest for homomorphic cryptosystems, data authentication and user privacy. Prior to joining Chalmers, Elena has been an assistant professor at Lund University, and before that, a postdoctoral researcher in the crypto group at Aarhus University. Elena completed her PhD at Chalmers in 2019. Her motto is: det är lätt att vara efterklok (it’s easy to be wise in hindsight).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://epagnin.github.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Elena Pagnin&amp;rsquo;s webpage&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Analysis and Design of cryptographic and data hiding algorithms</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2024/2024-06-13-rhouma/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2024/2024-06-13-rhouma/</guid><description>&lt;p>Rhouma Rhouma is a senior lecturer in CSE, Chalmers/University of Gothenburg. Obtained the telecommunications engineering in 2003, master in 2004, PhD in 2008 and a Habilitation in 2012 from the ENIT (Ecole Nationale d’Ingenieurs de Tunis), University of tunis el manar. He worked for 14 years across many universities in Tunisia. Visiting professor in the Lebanese university of Nouakchott in Mauritaniya for two years. He was with the UTAS in the sultanate of Oman from 2018 to 2024 before joining Chalmers/GU. His main research is cryptography, cryptanalysis, Digital watermarking and Data hiding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://sites.google.com/site/rhoouma/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rhouma Rhouma&amp;rsquo;s webpage&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mutual Contact Discovery</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2023/2023-10-16-jaap-henk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2023/2023-10-16-jaap-henk/</guid><description>&lt;p>Jaap-Henk Hoepman is guest professor at the PRISEC - Privacy And Security group of Karlstad University, Sweden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He is also an associate professor of privacy enhancing protocols and privacy by design in the Digital Security group at the Institute for Computing and Information Sciences of the Radboud University Nijmegen, principal scientist of the Privacy &amp;amp; Identity Lab, and member of iHub, Radboud University’s interdisciplinary research hub on Digitalization and Society.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moreover he is an associate professor in the IT Law section of the Transboundary Legal Studies department of the Faculty of Law of the University of Groningen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>His main research interest are privacy by design, privacy friendly protocols and identity management.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He also writes a lot about the societal impact of new technologies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.cs.ru.nl/J.H.Hoepman/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jaap-Henk Hoepman&amp;rsquo;s webpage&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Publicly Auditable Privacy Revocation</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2023/2023-01-19-joakim/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2023/2023-01-19-joakim/</guid><description>&lt;p>Joakim Brorsson is a PhD student at Lund University, co-supervised by Elena Pagnin at Chalmers University. His research interests lie in security and cryptographic methods to reduce trust in third parties.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Applying Cryptography’s Real/Ideal Paradigm to PL Security</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2022/2022-11-23-alley/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2022/2022-11-23-alley/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://alleystoughton.us/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Alley Stoughton&lt;/a> is a research professor at Boston University. She earned her doctorate in computer science from University of Edinburgh in 1987, and has a background in programming language semantics and functional programming. But in recent years her focus has been on security, mainly using the EasyCrypt proof assistant to prove the security of cryptographic protocols.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>LogPicker: Strengthening Certificate Transparency Against Covert Adversaries</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2022/2022-03-04-alexandra/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2022/2022-03-04-alexandra/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.tu-braunschweig.de/en/ias/staff/alexandra-dirksen" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Alexandra Dirksen&lt;/a>
is a PhD Candidate at &lt;a href="https://www.tu-braunschweig.de/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TU Braunschweig&lt;/a>
and is currently working in the field of Web Security &amp;amp; Privacy, Web
PKI and Large Scale Adversaries. Her further interests are different
topics of Applied Cryptography and Ethics in Computer Science. She is
currently part of the &lt;a href="https://kiwi-project.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">KIWI Project&lt;/a>, where
she works on mechanisms to detect security issues in OAuth protocol
flows at runtime.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Progressive and Efficient Verification of Digital Signatures</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2022/2022-02-04-elena/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2022/2022-02-04-elena/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://epagnin.github.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Elena Pagnin&lt;/a> is currently an assistant professor at Lund University (Sweden). Here she is an active member of the CRYSPY lab (CRYptography Security and PrivacY). Her research is focused on cryptography and security, with a special interest for homomorphic cryptosystems, data authentication and user privacy. Prior to joining Lund University, Elena has been a post doctoral researcher in the crypto group at Aarhus University (Denmark). Elena completed her PhD at Chalmers (Göteborg, Sweden) in 2019. Her motto is: det är lätt att vara efterklok (it’s easy to be wise in hindsight).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High-Assurance Cryptography Software in the Spectre Era</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2021/2021-06-11-css-talk44/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2021/2021-06-11-css-talk44/</guid><description>&lt;p>To appear in the Proceedings of the IEEE Symposium on Security and
Privacy, 2021. &lt;a href="https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/1104">https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/1104&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>