<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Privacy | Chalmers Security &amp; Privacy Lab</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/tag/privacy/</link><atom:link href="https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/tag/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Privacy</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 13:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/media/icon_huf405b5a3d64669240eafa59ffeef17e8_561926_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url><title>Privacy</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/tag/privacy/</link></image><item><title>Practical problems in enforcing Data Protection by Design &amp; by Default - the perspective of a Data Protection Authority</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2022/2022-09-23-marit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2022/2022-09-23-marit/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since 2015 &lt;a href="https://www.hansen-kronshagen.de/marit/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Marit Hansen&lt;/a> has been the State Data Protection Commissioner of Land Schleswig-Holstein and Chief of Unabhängiges Landeszentrum für Datenschutz (ULD). Before being appointed Data Protection Commissioner, she had been Deputy Commissioner for seven years. Since her diploma in computer science in 1995 Marit has been working on privacy and security aspects. Her focus is on “data protection by design” and “data protection by default” from both the technical and the legal perspectives. She often gives talks and has been lecturing at various universities and academies and has contributed to several EU and national research projects. Marit was member of the Data Ethics Commission of the German Government. Her contribution to education and research on privacy-enhancing technologies has awarded her an honorary doctorate from Karlstad University, Sweden.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>With a Little Help from My Friends: Transport Deniability for Instant Messaging</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2022/2022-02-11-boel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2022/2022-02-11-boel/</guid><description>&lt;p>Boel Nelson is a postdoc at Aarhus University. Her research interests include privacy enhancing technologies, data privacy, and real-world applications of security and privacy techniques.
Boel graduated with a PhD (topic: differential privacy) from Chalmers University of Technology in 2021. She holds a MSc in Computer Science and Engineering, and a BSc in Software Engineering, also from Chalmers University of Technology.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Challenges of User-centric Privacy Enhancing Technologies</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2021/2021-09-17-css-talk46/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2021/2021-09-17-css-talk46/</guid><description>&lt;p>Simone Fischer-Hübner&amp;rsquo;s Honorary Doctorate Lecture.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other honorary doctors will speak before and after Simone - feel free
to attend the whole event 4pm-6pm! (If you attend in person, please do
come at 4pm.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Limited seats, register via &lt;a href="mailto:events@chalmers.se">events@chalmers.se&lt;/a> to attend in person.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>