<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>legal evidence | Chalmers Security &amp; Privacy Lab</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/tag/legal-evidence/</link><atom:link href="https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/tag/legal-evidence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>legal evidence</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 13:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/media/icon_huf405b5a3d64669240eafa59ffeef17e8_561926_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url><title>legal evidence</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/tag/legal-evidence/</link></image><item><title>Re-designing computer systems for reliable electronic evidence</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2024/2024-08-22-steven/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2024/2024-08-22-steven/</guid><description>&lt;p>Steven J. Murdoch is Professor of Security Engineering and head of the Information Security Research Group of University College London, working on payment system security, privacy-enhancing technologies, online safety, and the interaction between computer science and the law. He teaches on the UCL MSc in Information Security. His research interests include authentication/passwords, banking security, anonymous communications, censorship resistance and covert channels. He has worked with the OpenNet Initiative, investigating Internet censorship, and for the Tor Project, on improving the security and usability of the Tor anonymity system. His current research is on how computer systems can produce evidence to allow fair and efficient dispute resolution. Professor Murdoch was Chief Security Architect at Cronto, and following their acquisition of the technology he developed, he took on the role of Distinguished Scientist for OneSpan. He is a member of REPHRAIN, the National Research Centre on Privacy, Harm Reduction and Adversarial Influence Online. He is a director of the Open Rights Group, a UK-based digital campaigning organisation working to protect rights to privacy and free speech online and is a Fellow of the IET and BCS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://murdoch.is/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steven Murdoch&amp;rsquo;s webpage&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>