<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>consent | Chalmers Security &amp; Privacy Lab</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/tag/consent/</link><atom:link href="https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/tag/consent/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>consent</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 13:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/media/icon_huf405b5a3d64669240eafa59ffeef17e8_561926_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url><title>consent</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/tag/consent/</link></image><item><title>Beyond Notice and Consent: Towards More Usable Privacy Under European Data Protection and Platform Regulations</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2023/2023-12-14-christine/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2023/2023-12-14-christine/</guid><description>&lt;p>Christine Utz (she/her) is a postdoctoral researcher at the CISPA Helmholtz Center for Information Security in Saarbrücken, Germany. She holds bachelor&amp;rsquo;s and master&amp;rsquo;s degrees in information security and a PhD in computer science from Ruhr University Bochum, as well as a law degree from the University of Bayreuth. Her doctoral research concerned effects of the GDPR on third-party web tracking and was conducted within the framework of an interdisciplinary graduate school, SecHuman - Security for People in Cyberspace. She combines online measurements with methods from human-computer interaction to foster people&amp;rsquo;s awareness and agency regarding the processing of their personal data. Her work was published at leading venues for security &amp;amp; privacy and human-computer interaction and was repeatedly featured at the FTC PrivacyCon in Washington, DC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cispa.de/en/people/c01chut" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Christine Utz&amp;rsquo;s webpage&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data Collection via Forms with Data Minimization, Full Accuracy and Informed Consent</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2024/2024-08-30-benjamin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2024/2024-08-30-benjamin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Benjamin Nguyen is Professor at INSA Centre Val de Loire since 2014, member of the Inria PETSCRAFT team, and part of the Systems and Data Security group of the Laboratoire d&amp;rsquo;Informatique Fondamentale d&amp;rsquo;Orléans (LIFO). He graduated from Ecole Normale Supérieure de Paris-Saclay in 2000, received his Ph.D. in 2003 from University of Paris-Sud on the topic of Personal Web Data Management, and was Associate Professor at University of Versailles and Inria between 2004 and 2014. He was head of LIFO from 2016 to 2022, associate director of INSA Centre Val de Loire (from 2015 to 2019) and is now head of the Inria PETSCRAFT team. His research interests cover Privacy and Security in Information Management Systems and Applications, in particular the evaluation of anonymization techniques, and the design and implementation of large scale privacy by design information management systems using PETs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.benjamin-nguyen.fr/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Benjamin Nguyen&amp;rsquo;s webpage&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>