<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cyber-security | Chalmers Security &amp; Privacy Lab</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/tag/cyber-security/</link><atom:link href="https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/tag/cyber-security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>cyber-security</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 13:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/media/icon_huf405b5a3d64669240eafa59ffeef17e8_561926_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url><title>cyber-security</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/tag/cyber-security/</link></image><item><title>Fostering a community-based approach towards SME cybersecurity</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2025/2025-01-24-steven/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2025/2025-01-24-steven/</guid><description>&lt;p>Prof. Steven Furnell is Professor of Cyber Security in the School of Computer Science at the University of Nottingham. His research interests include security management and culture, usability of security and privacy, and technologies for user authentication and intrusion detection. He has authored over 400 papers in refereed international journals and conference proceedings, as well as various books, book chapters, and industry reports. Steve is the UK representative to Technical Committee 11 (security and privacy) within the International Federation for Information Processing, and a board member of the Chartered Institute of Information Security, and a member of the Steering Group for the Cyber Security Body of Knowledge (CyBOK) and the Careers and Learning Working Group within the UK Cyber Security Council. Steve is the Principal Investigator on the CyCOS project, looking at enhancing cyber security support for small organisations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.nottingham.ac.uk/computerscience/people/steven.furnell" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steven Furnell&amp;rsquo;s webpage&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>