<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>information security | Chalmers Security Lab</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/tag/information-security/</link><atom:link href="https://www.cse.chalmers.se/tag/information-security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>information security</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/media/icon_huf405b5a3d64669240eafa59ffeef17e8_561926_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url><title>information security</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/tag/information-security/</link></image><item><title>Buy the ticket, take the ride: 25 years in infosec</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/event/2021/2021-10-29-css-talk50/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/event/2021/2021-10-29-css-talk50/</guid><description>&lt;p>Iv치n Arce is Chief Technology Office (CTO) at Quarkslab, a french
information security company specialized in high value-added security
consulting services and products. Ivan is responsible for integrating
the company&amp;rsquo;s security analysis know-how into Quark Flow, Quarkslab&amp;rsquo;s
scalable security analysis platform. Prior to joining Quarkslab, Arce
created and lead &amp;ldquo;Programa STIC&amp;rdquo; (Security in ICT Program) at
Fundaci칩n Sadosky, a non-for-profit organization of the Ministry of
Science and Technology of Argentina. Before joining Fundaci칩n
Sadosky, Arce co-founded Core Security Technologies, an infosec
company from Argentina, where he worked for 16 years in multiple
roles, ranging from security consultant and software developer, to
director of security consulting services, VP of Engineering and CTO.
During his tenure at Core Security, the company grew from a team of 5
security consultants to a services and products company with over a
hundred employees that created and popularized a new market segment
(penetration testing software), pioneered industry-lead vulnerability
and exploit research &amp;amp; disclosure, and serviced thousands of customers
worldwide. Prior to founding Core Security, he worked at a computer
telephony integration startup while studying Electronic Engineering at
University of Buenos Aires, Argentina.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Iv치n was a founding editorial board member of the IEEE Security &amp;amp;
Privacy magazine, co-editor of the Attack Trends department for ~10
years, and co-founder of the IEEE Center for Secure Design. He is
author of numerous articles and papers and a frequent speaker at
infosec industry and practitioner conferences.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>