<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>IoT | Chalmers Security Lab</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/hugo/tag/iot/</link><atom:link href="https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/hugo/tag/iot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>IoT</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 13:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/hugo/media/icon_huf405b5a3d64669240eafa59ffeef17e8_561926_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url><title>IoT</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/hugo/tag/iot/</link></image><item><title>Building Practical Security Systems for the Post-app Smart Home</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/hugo/event/2021/2021-12-10/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/hugo/event/2021/2021-12-10/</guid><description>&lt;p>Adwait Nadkarni is an Assistant Professor in the Department of Computer Science, and director of the Secure Platforms Lab (SPL) at William &amp;amp; Mary. Prof. Nadkarni’s primary research domain is security and privacy, with a focus on emerging platforms, and the areas of operating systems and software security. His research is generously supported by the National Science Foundation (NSF) and the Commonwealth of Virginia’s Cyber Initiative (CCI). Prior to joining William &amp;amp; Mary, Prof. Nadkarni earned his Bachelor of Engineering (BE) in Computer Engineering from the University of Mumbai in July 2011, followed by his Ph.D. and M.S. in Computer Science from the Computer Science Department at the North Carolina State University in May 2017 and December 2012 respectively, both with Dr. William Enck. At NC State, Prof. Nadkarni was a founding member of the Wolfpack Security and Privacy Research (WSPR) Lab, and served as its Lead Graduate Student until May 2017.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>