<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>IoT | Chalmers Security &amp; Privacy Lab</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/tag/iot/</link><atom:link href="https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/tag/iot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>IoT</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 14:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/media/icon_huf405b5a3d64669240eafa59ffeef17e8_561926_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url><title>IoT</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/tag/iot/</link></image><item><title>Ransomware Protection and Anomaly Detection in Networks of Severely Constrained Wireless Embedded Devices</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2024/2024-04-12-george/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2024/2024-04-12-george/</guid><description>&lt;p>George&amp;rsquo;s research focuses on energy-efficient networking and security for severely constrained wireless embedded devices and the IoT, with an emphasis on industrial applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>His objective is to invent and prototype algorithms that are optimised for constrained/low-capability, battery-powered devices without sacrificing performance and reliability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the last few years he has been focussing on IEEE 802.15.4 / .15.4g networks, doing work that covers the entire 6LoWPAN/RPL stack. More specifically, he has made contributions in the areas of multicast forwarding; MAC layers with time-synchronisation (such as TSCH); congestion control; routing; neighbour discovery; service discovery. Within the same IoT context, he is also interested in secure software writing techniques; digital forensics; and software defined networking.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot of his work has been released as open source software and is distributed as part of the Contiki-NG operating system for the Internet of Things, an open-source project of which he iis a co-founder and steering group member. Most of the work is also part of the original Contiki OS, for which he used to serve as maintainer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://research-information.bris.ac.uk/en/persons/george-oikonomou" target="_blank" rel="noopener">George Oikonomou&amp;rsquo;s webpage&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building Practical Security Systems for the Post-app Smart Home</title><link>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2021/2021-12-10/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cse.chalmers.se/research/group/security/event/2021/2021-12-10/</guid><description>&lt;p>Adwait Nadkarni is an Assistant Professor in the Department of Computer Science, and director of the Secure Platforms Lab (SPL) at William &amp;amp; Mary. Prof. Nadkarni’s primary research domain is security and privacy, with a focus on emerging platforms, and the areas of operating systems and software security. His research is generously supported by the National Science Foundation (NSF) and the Commonwealth of Virginia’s Cyber Initiative (CCI). Prior to joining William &amp;amp; Mary, Prof. Nadkarni earned his Bachelor of Engineering (BE) in Computer Engineering from the University of Mumbai in July 2011, followed by his Ph.D. and M.S. in Computer Science from the Computer Science Department at the North Carolina State University in May 2017 and December 2012 respectively, both with Dr. William Enck. At NC State, Prof. Nadkarni was a founding member of the Wolfpack Security and Privacy Research (WSPR) Lab, and served as its Lead Graduate Student until May 2017.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>